THEME SONG: In the not too
distant future, next Sunday AD,
there was a guy named Joel, not
too different from you or me.
He worked at Gizmonic
Institute, just another face
in a red jumpsuit.
He did a good job
cleaning up the place.
But his bosses didn't like him
so they shot him into space.
We'll send him cheesy movies,
the worst we can find.
La-la-la.
He'll have to sit
and watch them all.
And we'll monitor his mind.
La-la-la.
Now, keep in mind Joel can't
control where the movies being
or end.
La-la-la.
Because he used
those special parts
to make his robot friends.
Robot Roll Call.
All right, let's go!
Cambot.
Pan Left!
Gypsy!
Hi, girl!
Tom Servo.
What a cool guy!
Crow!
He's a wisecracker.
If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes,
and other science facts.
La-la-la.
Then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show.
I should really just relax for
Mystery Science Theater 3000!
Then we'll talk to Moms Mabley, and she'll tell us how she kept up a good attitude despite being dead for 20 years.
The circus is in town, and I'm going on location cleaning up after those big bull elephants.
Then later, Robert Goulet will be stopping by and swinging into high,
Singing a song and then showing his famous Bloody Mary mix.
I hope he sings the song first, if you will.
I know what you mean.
Three seconds to commercial sign.
And for you bachelors, we're expecting a visit from Wanda McHale and her whale of a tale.
So start your popcorn poppin' now, boys.
And I'll be on location. A man who ate his weight in Silly Putty? We'll see it.
I bet he can, you know, take impressions of newspapers right off his elbow or something like that.
Anyway, on a sadder note, Moms Mabley's attitude really isn't doing all that well.
Oh, yeah, well, maybe she should try Robert Goulet's Bloody Mary mix.
In five, four, three, two, commercial sign out.
All these stories and more. Not.
So, Joel, what's pain again?
Pain is an intensely uncomfortable feeling, and it's something you want to stop immediately.
Show me.
You're a robot. You know you can't feel pain. I can't do that.
Come on, Joel. Show him.
Okay, pain is something like this.
Come on, the mads are calling. Here's some people that know about pain.
Well, these bandages are ready to come off now. Frank, just head off that direction.
A little problem getting the rosy rear head to take.
And how about you? Are you ready for this week's Invention Exchange, Katrina?
Oh, yeah, I've got an Invention Exchange this week.
If you're like me, and I know I am, there are certain days you come home from school or work,
and it suddenly dawns on you to have a Halloween party to go to.
So I've come up with some easy Halloween costumes you can make with stuff around the house.
Like this one, Crow will be my model for this one.
Just take some candy wrappers, and you tape them to yourself, or your jacket, or your dress,
if you happen to be a human, like that.
And then adorn yourself with some silly string.
[Laughter]
Like that. Open.
And then you face the camera, and then you can go as the floor of a movie theater.
[Laughter]
And then you get this one. Take a milk cart and put a slit or a hole in the back, cut a hole in the front,
wear it over your head, and see, you go as a missing child.
Have you seen me?
See? And this one takes a little more preparation.
Take some aluminum foil, I like to use the Reynolds wrap, and a pie pan, and you cut the center out of the pie pan.
Then you wrap the foil around your head.
Like that. I know I probably sound like a kazoo, right?
A little bit.
Anyway, I am Iron Man!
[Laughter]
Then you get the pie pan.
Right there. On the desk.
There you go. Close. Warm.
It's a good idea to put this on after you finally get to the party, too.
I bet.
You take the pie pan and put it around your neck, and you go as Giffy Pop popcorn.
[Laughter]
What do you think, sirs?
I saw some hack do that at the Funny Bone in St. Louis.
[Laughter]
Frank, go get your costume on.
The lizard costume?
No, the other one.
Oh, okay.
Well, panzer, my invention exchange this week is another easy-to-make costume.
Hey, you copied that!
Cheaters, cheaters.
What? What are you saying?
That you're the only one to come up with a Halloween costume by using stuff found around the house?
I came up with this when you were back in short pants.
Can you guess what I am? Can you guess?
Well, by taking two lengths of ABS drainage tubing and fastening them to my arms and keeping my feet together real close,
I go as the goalie of a foosball team, huh? You get it, Frank? Huh?
And by wearing this ordinary everyday Fram air filter, I get to dress up as Lieutenant Commander Geordi LaForge of TV's Star Trek The Next Generation,
starring TV's LeVar Burton.
Kids, reading opens up a rainbow of enchantment and whimsy and wonder and wisdom and--
Thank you, Kunta Kinte.
Well, your film this week, Joel, burns deep in the fine tradition of Kramer versus Kramer,
Ollie versus Norton, Kasparov versus Karpov, it's Megalon versus Godzilla.
It'll make you laugh, it'll make you cry, and maybe, just maybe, teach you a little something about yourself.
And kids, don't forget to read Godzilla versus the Velveteen Rabbit.
[alarm]
In the first part of 1971, on a small island near the Aleutians, the second underground nuclear test took place.
But it wasn't as good as the first one.
This is what happened.
Oh!
Oh, it blew up. What'd you expect?
Okay, we're impressed.
Beautiful.
Wow.
Oof.
Look, Jacuzzi of the Gods.
The effects of the explosion were widespread, even on faraway monster island in the South Pacific.
Whenever they test nuclear bombs, it's the monsters who suffer.
Yeah, yeah, paint that the way.
War is not good for monsters and other living things.
That's the beasts?
They're the monsters.
Oh.
Hey, knock it off. You think decent people don't work?
Stop the madness, stop monster island, I want to get off.
Damn, kids, will you loud rock music?
Ah, Spiny Norman.
Uh-oh.
Godzilla's back and someone's got to pay.
He's cheesed.
You know, I kind of feel like this opening segment is a metaphor for our souls.
Ooh, heavy.
Wow.
Ooh.
Ah.
Grand Finale.
Screamers.
I don't know.
Well, the credits should be exploding soon.
There they are.
What did I know there?
A film by Ingemeyer Bergman.
Wow.
Dramatic.
We're now right here on our stage, Topo Isio.
Topo.
Oh.
Okay, technologically advanced people, huh? Give me a break.
They can make high-deficient TV, but they can't make decent water toys.
You can see their wheel-o.
I can see. Keeps driving me for your life.
Have a drink.
Want to try?
Yeah, why not?
Why not? I'm high.
He's drowning. Neat.
Hey, stole Wayne Newton's suit.
A drink?
Yeah.
Let's do some shooters.
Hmm?
Uh-oh.
Hey, is this stuff three-two?
The bull.
A quake?
No, quiz.
No, picnic on a slide.
Rock on.
You don't have to put on the red dress.
Come back.
Great.
What am I supposed to do? I'm on a plastic porpoise.
Help me.
Come on, flipper. Save him.
Hmm.
What else for a dolphin?
Hey, the rocket.
Oh, rockets.
You want a picnic?
Great. Let's put him out of our misery.
Or his misery.
Help me.
Hurry up.
Hey, you're in no position to make demands, kid.
What's that?
Hmm.
Uh-oh.
Looks like trouble.
Dry ice and lots of it.
Keep working those thingamabobs.
Wow.
Ooh.
Well, this is what happens when you go in the water
less than a half hour before eating.
Yeah.
Or after eating.
Hmm.
Hey, this is better than the girls.
Try not to get sucked into the vortex of hell, Billy.
I think Billy's gonna be a boil in a bag dinner soon.
Yep.
Hey, catch.
Why did the--
Ow.
I guess a rocket is standard picnicking equipment in Japan, isn't it?
Yep.
Let's go on a picnic. Let's see.
We got our food, beverages, and 50 feet of uncoiled rope.
Yep.
[laughs]
Billy, this is no time to floss.
Come on.
Oh, now they can all die on dry land.
Get off that thing. It's rented. Come on.
Ooh.
Oh, grind the kid's knees into the lava rock while you're at it.
Jeepers.
Ooh.
Bubbling, bubbling pot.
Well, note to myself. Never vacation on an active volcano.
[laughs]
Hold me. Hold me.
Oh, no. Darn fool toy.
I love that thing.
Trying to save us.
Never before in the annals of Kiddom had a toy been sucked into the whirlpool of death.
Here he goes.
Ah, we're in the spin cycle.
Yeah, or else somebody took some hair out of the drain in the bottom.
I think so. That's what it is.
Plunge don't care what you're putting on there.
Well, they don't think this is going to help the tourists trade at all.
Yeah, I know. Plus, we're in a recession, so.
No, this watery manifestation of a vengeful, wrathful God couldn't have come at a worse time.
Huh?
Pretty sure.
Freshen up?
It's really hot, you know.
It's hot.
Niagara Falls. Slowly I turn, step by step, inch by inch.
Really makes you think, don't it? Maybe not.
This week, Moses starring in Don't Raise the Bridge, Lower the River.
That's Jerry Lewis.
Well, okay.
Could be Moses.
Breaks your heart, don't it? Drinks anybody?
We're going to need a tux pad the size of Tokyo.
In the land of Tofu Queen.
With Paul Horn on the flute.
Well, great. What does it have to do with us?
Well, I'll never get the deposit back on that stupid dolphin thrill toy.
Someday, Roxanne, this will all be yours.
I'm filled with shame, you know. I really am.
You imagine how I must feel.
Welcome to Death Valley. The driver is either gone or he's missing.
Well, let's leave that pain behind, huh? We're swinging into high.
The natural disaster behind them, they drove off in a speedy car.
...in many parts of the Pacific. It has been many lives have been lost. According to the National Science Bank Institute,
the disturbances run down will be caused by the nuclear gas.
Slow down.
They also warn that more tremors are expected.
Incredible, isn't it? What the hell are they trying to do? Wipe us all out or something?
I hate these wacky morning DJs.
They'll kill the whole world off when they submerge their land and drown us all.
Damn Japanese buying up everything.
Oh, what's that? Where are those places? I've never heard of them before.
I'll tell you. They were continents that existed a long time ago.
Condiments? You mean like ketchup and mustard?
One in the Pacific, one in the Indian Ocean.
Then one day there was a big earthquake and they both vanished.
Mind you, I must say, the majority of historians believe they only existed in legend.
The historians existed in legend?
I wish this music existed in legend.
The condiments.
I'll only say of Yusef Lateef on the flute here.
Who?
Never mind.
Must be a blue moon out.
I think it was shot blue for a night.
Yeah.
Hey, listen. It would be funny if the earthquake destroyed your robot.
Yeah, it would be funny if the earthquake killed your family.
Ooh, I hate those masters.
Hey, look.
What?
Look at the door. It's open.
Oh my God, the humidifier committed suicide!
It's Oscar Wilde.
Anytime.
Fight.
Uh-oh.
Hi, Kiba!
Hit him with the humidifier.
I have just been liberated by the power of Vix.
Cool.
Goro.
Mommy.
Mommy. No, Mommy. No.
Not the kabuki mask. No.
You okay?
Huh?
Okay.
Roxanne.
Seems to be okay.
Except he's got a concussion.
Right.
I still hate these stairs.
It's such a nuisance.
I gotta change that.
Well, I hope he doesn't ruin Wayne Newton's jacket.
No.
Huh?
Damn.
Got to find out where he shops.
Whoa!
Go, Speed Racer!
Ha ha!
Here he goes.
Mahigo go.
Mahigo go go go.
He's a demon.
Well, it's a good thing they cleverly hid that robot.
Oof. Well, I really meant a mess at this place.
Or was it you, you naughty, naughty robot?
Damn, and the cleaning lady doesn't come till Thursday.
Well, let's clean up.
[growling]
I'm going to do everything he does.
Listen, those guys really made a mess of my room too.
Well, why?
Yeah.
Yeah, whatever.
It seems to be stolen.
That right?
Still, we better make a thorough check.
Okay.
Let's start with your larynx, kid.
Whoa.
Huh?
What?
Well, guys, I guess no matter how hard you try,
there's just no way to make parallel parking exciting.
Let's see.
Boy's life, popular science, highlights,
my own autopsy report.
Huh?
Hey, look.
I found some funny powder.
Uh, that's mine.
Just leave it alone there.
What do you think it could be?
Those are pop rocks, you idiot.
Yeah, that makes a funny noise.
[screeching]
[growling]
You know, all these screeches are on the soundtrack album.
Oh.
Wait a minute.
Jazzy.
Jazzy?
Hey, it's Pluto.
Huh?
[laughing]
You're embarrassed.
U-tain, try something.
Whoa.
U-tain very volatile.
Good thing he had the fun mobile.
Yeah.
[panting]
Looks like a fire.
Damn.
You all to hell.
Oh.
Hmm.
I just don't get it at all.
They're cigarettes, don't you?
Well, they wouldn't go to this trouble for nothing.
They must have been after something of yours.
Got it.
Well, what's this?
Hmm?
One of them must have dropped a butt.
Now shut up and finish your Laffy Taffy, kid.
Hey, look.
It's the same color as that bit of sand I found.
[all saying "the same color as that bit of sand"]
So it is.
You found some sand?
Hey, shh.
It's...
It's God's watching.
This is it?
No, I think they got this shot from an old Jackie Gleason show.
Leaving my bar is sort of red.
Probably off their shoes.
I found it over near the robot.
Hmm.
According to Dr. Helstrom, these bugs will take over the world.
Ooh.
Let's see. That's me and that's him.
Industry creating a better world.
Our most valuable resource?
People.
He's a maniac, a maniac.
And he's dancing like he's never danced before.
He's a steel town boy on a Saturday.
[clears throat]
They've just created Jennifer Beals.
Wow.
Now this controls his kung fu grip.
Hi there.
Hi.
There.
Oh?
E, R, and sometimes Y.
What's all this?
Baby rider.
How's it work?
Baby rider?
You should know. You're a racing driver.
Oh, yeah. But I'm only an amateur.
I had enough in the water.
I'm going to sticky dry land.
You really think it'll go?
You bet your life.
Say the secret word and win $100.
I don't know.
I do.
Oh, how I loathe him.
I'm going to test it out. Bye-bye.
Take care.
Don't forget to ride towards traffic.
Damn stick.
Now let's see.
I'll sell AT&T.
I'll buy a little bit more of American Cant.
Huh?
It's the all idiot channel.
Oh, come in.
Okay.
Hi, it's me again.
Hi there.
Can I come in?
Oh, nearly finished, eh?
Mm-hmm.
Hi.
We'll be checking over that sand we found here.
Huh?
It's from a strata 30 miles below the seabed.
Hey, you sure?
Yeah.
The only other place you'll find it is on Easter Island.
Hey, Al is reading your lips.
Where's that?
It's an uninhabited island 2,000 miles east of Tahiti.
Down the bunny trail.
It's mainly famous because of a very peculiar discovery
that was made there.
Dd7.
Some huge statues...
Let's go there now through the miracle of television.
They're said to be over three million years old.
Well, that doesn't help one bit.
It makes it worse.
I miss our Sunday drives.
Oh, baby.
Oh, when we see love and find love, make love, baby.
You put Barry White there.
Thank you.
Great.
You made it at last.
Yeah, and he does parties, too.
You know what?
I'll call him Jet Jaguar.
Jet Jaguar, eh?
Not bad.
You're right.
It suits him.
That's a great name.
Jet Jaguar?
What a stupid name.
I feel good about myself.
I like myself.
Uh-oh.
Guys, the TV cameras.
Also, it has automatic evasion devices,
so it'll always get out of your way.
Hope so.
But as far as I'm concerned, it's got right of way.
You said it, my little hard-bodied bachelor friend.
Oh, that's our cue to go.
Let's get out of here.
I have shamed the family.
Get out. Get out.
Come on in.
It's unlocked.
Oh, wow.
Gosh, look at that.
Boy, I never knew that they could...
Oh, oh, oh.
She's a...
Ditch the pigs.
Hey, what are you two high-speed bit-blitters up to anyway?
Oh, uh, we're just finishing our monster drawings.
Yeah, that's not right there.
Monster drawings?
These monster drawings?
Uh, yeah, yeah, that's right.
The movie inspired us to create our own mega monsters,
and mine is the grandest of all.
Well, it sounds pretty neat.
Could I check them out?
Oh, well, mine needs a little set-up.
Let me explain it here.
Mine is green, and he stands 18 feet tall,
and he has flames shooting out of it.
Uh, neat.
Yeah, uh, well, mine has flames, too,
and it's 20 feet tall and has a big claw thingy.
Huh, huh.
Well, uh, mine has two claw thingies,
and he uses them to eat railroad trains.
Oh, um, well, mine has a secret that, um,
there's an elf in his head.
An elf in his head.
Oh, what?
An elf.
He's got an elf,
and a trillion times the atom-bound power.
Oh, um, and it's got a hydraulic tail-stopper.
Oh, sure.
Mine is a million-jillion times more powerful than that
any day of the week.
Oh, yeah, well, mine is the number before infinity.
Oh, yeah, well, my monster's a meltdown
of all the Terrytoon characters.
Well, my monster is silent as tomorrow.
He kills in the night.
He has been acquainted with the night.
Sounds like your monster reads Frost, too.
Uh, yeah, and he sprays it like icy death
from his bloody stumps.
Oh, right.
Well, mine is called Gorblet,
and he was spawned from a giant mutant hell beast
and comes to Earth every so often to kill.
He must drink the blood of the innocent to live.
Every so often?
Yeah, you know, whenever he needs to.
Well, my monster's a 24-hour wide-awake nightmare,
and it has all that stuff that I just mentioned,
plus it has power to completely kill your monster
ten times over.
Oh, yeah, well, my monster is so completely scary
that even thinking about it could kill you.
Oh, I bet. Cannot.
Can't solve.
Not. Not.
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Okay, all right, you win.
You win the world.
Your monster is the best, kills everything,
and you're happy, and you're standing there
all in your shame.
Are you happy now?
Yeah, I am, as a matter of fact.
Listen to you guys.
I don't even want to hear this, uh...
You just can go discuss this as long as you want.
I got to get out of here.
Okay.
Whew, that was close.
I'm glad he's gone.
I thought he'd never go.
Yeah.
Let's take a look at his mom.
What'd you do with those?
They're right here.
Boy, you really come up with some stupid things sometimes.
I see death from bloody stumps.
How dumb.
Hey, I thought that was pretty good.
No, I don't think so.
Yes, I'm sorry, it was good.
No, no, it wasn't good.
Yes.
Uh-uh, uh-uh.
Yes!
(Gibberish)
Now quit fighting, you idiot.
Hey, hey, you're stupid.
Baby, you're stupid.
Baby, you idiot.
Ooh, what's going on?
Huh.
Hey, did I get you?
Now I can listen to their cable all day.
I think they get the national network.
C-topia.
C-topia, C-topia, run.
We're leaving you well.
Run, Topia, run.
Everything's going well.
Except my hair.
We've managed to occupy the laboratory,
and we have the inventor too.
That's good.
One problem, though.
You caught us in the middle of our production
of "La Cogra Foe."
Hmm.
Houston.
Hi, I'm Styro.
Whoa!
A brand from Uncle Penn.
Yikes.
Geez, look at the size of that guy's neck.
Wow.
Say, these Klan meetings have really lightened up.
Very festive.
Yeah, and you know that now that
Twilight Tharp has joined the Klan,
Anna Kisselgauf should give him a good review.
Huh?
I've got a good thing going.
These Bob Mackigons are fabulous.
Fabulous.
I'm Dorf.
And it's the June Taylor-Lynchers.
There you go.
All right, everyone, places.
Remember, Ziegfeld's in the house tonight.
Thank you, girls.
Our people, today, C-Topia...
Tomorrow, Broadway.
After three million years of peace,
we finally have to fight.
We don't want to,
but the people of Earth leave us no choice.
The sanctions are just not working.
...they have already destroyed a third of our country.
You just have to take my word for it.
No more.
C-Topia will strike back.
For today, the Earthmen now will have to take their own medicine.
Will harm them.
For I will unleash Megalon to protect our land,
our underwater world.
Great.
They're gonna take over the world with interpretive dance.
Megalon.
God of draperies.
Ah, keep your shirt off.
I'm coming.
Wait, now. Megalon.
What is this?
My wake-up call was for seven.
Great.
Come on, rise up now.
To the Earth, sir.
Destroy the Earth.
Destroy our enemies.
Rise up.
At least send us a lava lamp or something, please.
Go on.
Megalon.
Come on, you wuss.
Whoa.
It's murky.
God, watch it.
This guy does not know how to make a normal entrance.
Whoa.
If Siegfried and Ryan got a wake-up call,
I think it would look something like this.
Ooh, whoa.
I would say eye protection should be worn in this area.
Jules Podell presents Jubilee 90.
(thunder rumbling)
Ta-da.
Oh, boy, do I have a hangover.
Oh.
It's Edward Scissorhands.
Huh, what a hothead.
(laughs)
Oh, he looks kind of like a Christmas tree monster.
Hey, and his arms look like the Chrysler Building.
Ah, ha.
Ooh, he awakes with the worst special effects of the morning.
Well, putting up my sleeve and presto.
Must be a seven and a half.
Hey, how about a little applause?
I did this act with David Copperfield in Reno
and got standing o's all week.
Thank you, I'll be in Atlantic City next week
with funny man Jimmy Walker.
Thanks.
Wow.
Neat, huh?
So it was all a dream, huh?
Yeah.
Wow.
Uh-oh.
Say.
(clears throat)
Oh, excuse me.
Huh?
Ooh.
If I could only get to my utility belt,
I invented it, you know.
Batman stole it from me.
Sour grapes.
(muffled yelling)
Hey, we've been performing Houdini's Metamorphosis for years.
Now we both end up tied in a box.
Ironic.
I can see myself in this floor.
Oh, they're in a fry pan.
Hmm.
Wearing some kind of metal box.
Hmm, good.
What are we going to do?
I reckon they mean to kill us.
You reckon?
Hey, you're Japanese, Ebson.
Now then, get busy.
Work on this rope.
What, do you want the tighter?
Good, now we can watch the importance of being earnest on video.
Yeah.
This is my Kraft American singles machine.
It's Swiss.
Operation the Goofy Game for Japanese Oscar-wall look-alikes.
Oh, do I hate these stairs.
I'm a robot and I hate these stairs.
Now get the mail.
What a day.
What a day. I feel grand.
God, I love my job.
Oh, great, you tied us together.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you very much.
That was surprisingly.
Yukio has left the stadium.
Meanwhile, BJ and the bear go to Japan.
In breaking training.
I'm getting leg burns on my teeth.
Are you all right there?
I have to go to the bedroom.
Keep going.
Hey, how is all three of them can be driving?
Well, the way I see it, it's none of our business anyway.
I mean, we're getting 100,000 yen.
Yeah, real funny.
That's like four bucks or something.
Now I'm going to read you parts of Picture of Dorian Gray
and I want you to be honest with me.
I thought I'd get a better table than this.
I can't even see the stage.
Well, where are the others now?
They're in the truck.
Okay, it's then done.
Okay, got to go. Call me if you survive, kid.
We're cruising at 50,000 feet.
Geez, I really got to go.
Reporting. The robot is at the lake.
All's ready.
Well done.
The inventor will be there soon.
He's on his way now with a brother.
With a bra?
Our elevator is already moving upwards
and will emerge from a crack in the lake bed.
You've been the raspberry seed in my wisdom tooth for long enough.
Where are you taking my friends?
To the kingdom of Cetopia.
That sounds neat.
Cetopia.
That's right.
It's a country below the surface of the sea.
It was engulfed in an earthquake millions of years ago
and most of its people survived.
They managed to create their own oxygen supply
and later were able to construct their own sun.
So the legend's true.
We're a very advanced people.
Except for our haircuts.
Your fact is much superior to yours.
Well, if you're so damn clever, why steal our robot?
That's a good point.
We have few people.
We need to have robots in order to build up an army
and we don't have the time to invent them.
Oh, yeah?
You mean you're too dumb?
Okay, we may be advanced, but we don't take sarcasm well.
I wasn't being sarcastic, you jerk.
All I'm saying is if you're going to be criticized,
you'll have to cushion it a bit.
Come on, we're sensitive.
Mwah!
Gotta run.
Wrong way.
Over here.
Oh, okay, good.
All these stairs.
Steps are real pain.
Hey, someone stole the top of his car.
And he's on the wrong side.
All right.
Right, that's got it.
Look out!
Oh!
[roaring]
[screaming]
Watch your head.
Oh!
Help me!
Lie still.
Either these drapes go or I do.
I'm having trouble lifting up to my China--
Huh?
Oh, I have such a beef over.
Unit one.
Unit one?
Unit one here.
Come in, please.
My prisoner has just escaped.
He'll try to rescue the inventor of the robot.
He's also aware of the whole story of our mission here.
I can't do it.
Let's get him, chatty.
Oh, I see now.
I haven't seen this already.
Come on.
Rex Dart, Eskimo spy.
Oh, another one.
Seen that.
I'm huge.
[chuckles]
Hey, I'm feeling pretty good.
[roaring]
Rex Dart pops the clutch and tells the thogs to eat his dust.
[cheering]
Woohoo!
[roaring]
Action sequences filmed in ConfusoVision.
Wow, it sounds like the Allman brothers are doing the background music.
Yeah, in fact, that's Dwayne Allman on the motorcycle there.
[laughs]
A little...
Sorry.
Maybe it's Barry Oakley.
Oh, you knew my little shortcut.
[roaring]
Uh-oh.
[laughs]
This is no place for a convertible.
You know, I think Peter Bogdanovich shot this sequence here.
That's why it's so funny.
[choking]
Not.
You know, in France, this scene would be considered genius.
Yeah.
I have to remember that route.
It cuts 15 minutes off my drive time.
[choking]
Suddenly, we're watching "Manix."
You know, in France, Mike Conners is considered genius.
Mike Conners?
Is. Manix.
[chuckles]
Well, there's a lot of congestion on the interstate this morning.
You might want to consider taking an alternate route,
say, down the side of a steep mountain.
The man who drove down Everest.
I haven't seen this much action since Herbie Goes to Mexico.
You know, in France, Dean Jones is considered...
Joel, shut up.
Yeah.
[choking]
It's not funny.
Whoa.
Hey, guys, it's Steve McQueen.
You know, Steve McQueen is considered...
[coughing]
There really is construction.
Eat a peach, dude.
Whoo!
Oh, he's okay.
Gary Busey is back on the bike.
[chuckles]
Gary Busey is not considered genius.
Oh, look out, Herbie.
[laughing]
Huh?
Uh...
It kooks me out.
[chuckling]
Huh?
What get?
[laughing]
Better luck next time, kooky.
What a mess.
The gods do not approve of this inept car chase sequence.
Ooh.
All right, forget everything you've seen until now.
That's right, it's time for the headliner.
For my first trick, I will use an ordinary metropolitan city.
It's great.
Oh, change the channel.
I hate it here at the improv.
I'll guide you to Tokyo immediately.
Tokyo?
Winged freak.
Wait till they get a load of me.
Hey!
Curse you, Jet Jaguar, and everything you stand for.
[chuckles]
Hmm.
Atomic batteries to power.
Curvans to speed.
Ready to go, then.
Yep.
Um, not pretty, but, uh, get me there.
All right.
Follow me.
Now, why is Pavarotti holding these guys hostage?
They hate opera?
Ooh.
Run, everybody, run!
Pink Lady and Jepa back!
Ahh!
Or Pink Lady and Death.
[laughs]
Wait, security is tight at these Japanese rock concerts.
Yeah, they're going all the way to make sure McCartney
doesn't bring any more dope into the country.
You mean Linda?
That's probably it.
Look at that.
Huh, it's amazing what they're doing with HO scale these days.
Huh.
That's pretty fakie, isn't it?
Oh, come on, fakie!
Oh, fakie!
Ah, dumb.
Real.
Hey!
That's real.
I think this is footage from the war, perhaps.
Hey, General, where you going?
I'm going to Berlin to personally shoot that paper-hanging
son of a bitch.
[laughs]
Or not.
That was pretty good.
Told you we should have carpooled.
D'oh!
Huh?
Oh, fakie.
Flaky.
Oh, yeah.
You can see brush strokes.
Look, oh.
Big hair, right there.
Oh.
Yeah.
Saigon.
I can't believe I'm in a model of Saigon.
Oh, I sing La Traviata.
[singing]
Psst, hey, bud.
Huh?
Chinese fire drill.
[laughs]
Whoa, whoa.
They're going to attack the monster with a Fresnel light.
Yeah, I think it's a Baby Junior.
Oh.
Hey.
Everybody come.
Everybody.
Hey, the ups man is here.
I got some bullets on order.
The brown buffs.
Get up and fish in.
Grab your ankles.
[laughs]
Cute.
Phallic symbols at the ready, sir.
Good morning.
Boy, all this and they still can't get the comedy channel.
Mm, huh?
Oh.
I'm sorry.
[clears throat]
So are they setting all this up to repel
the boy and his brother or the monster or maybe us?
I don't know.
Over and out.
Language.
Know what?
We stopped moving.
Duh.
Smart kid.
Excuse me.
Button that up.
Scream.
Die maybe.
Quick.
Brace your legs.
Against the what?
[gunshot]
Huh?
Bye-bye.
You know, it's one of those houses
at the center of the universe where it's--
Oh, gravity is all weird?
[gunshot]
Huh?
Is that you?
[gunshot]
What?
Oh, that's really scary, isn't it?
Hmm.
What's going on?
Oh, it's just a big roach.
Monster!
No.
Did someone say monster?
I wet him.
Hey, mister, will you give us a ride, please?
That damn monster, he's here.
Where's the European gun?
We throw him out of the truck.
[gunshot]
Can I ride too?
It's a Volkswagen.
I'll fit.
Here's a preview of my Broadway show.
Yep, it's Megalund's Broadway, Aquitennial '91.
I'll be joined by my pals Ben Vereen, Hal Linden,
and Anita Gillette.
Well, see you later.
Bye-bye.
We got to go too.
Just get out of here.
Scooby-Saw.
Carry me.
No.
[tires squealing]
[music playing]
Stand by for action.
Rock star, Eskimo Spy.
[music playing]
Rex Dart, Eskimo Spy.
Rex Dart is Eskimo Spy.
[music playing]
Meat, huh?
[buzzer]
Oh, movie sign, let's go.
[music playing]
Oh.
It's great.
Yeah.
Neat, huh?
I need to see more of that car action.
Yeah, Rex Dart's cool.
Hey.
Uh-oh.
Damn monster.
Popped a clutch, engaged ignition, checked my blind spot.
It's flooded.
Let me go through.
Hey, you're going to buy tickets for the show or what?
I'm with myself again.
Don't give me any of that crap about high ticket prices.
It's a good show.
Uh-oh.
Damn busted.
You think it's cheap producing an effect like this?
And that's not even counting the cost of rehearsal space.
Why accompaniment?
Costumes, sets, dance, dance.
Thank you, thank you, crow.
Whee!
[laughing]
That's three times now.
It's starting to sting.
[thunder]
Pretty good.
Pretty impressive, huh?
Well, that was just the beginning.
I'll just sharpen these up for a little truck alimony.
Whoa.
It's up.
It might be, it could be.
It is, it's a home run.
Hey, hey.
No, that wasn't that bad.
I've got to call the theater guild or name it.
I have seen.
Ooh.
A bridge too far?
Not for me.
[laughing]
You know, that monster does not know the meaning of the word "arri."
Hmm.
Really doesn't.
This is no time to sleep, my little fairy princesses.
Roxas.
You don't have to wear that dress tonight.
My love.
Goro.
Darling.
You all right?
I'll live.
Great.
Hmm?
Where are you hiding?
Huh?
It's our boy.
I'm taunting you.
Taunt?
Isn't that Jack?
You were there?
No, it's another superhero of your own design.
Damn.
They're controlling him.
It's a pity we can't send you to Jaguar to go and get Godzilla.
Man, it's a pity we can't kill you and get away with it.
We'll try.
But how?
With this.
Your AA medallion?
I've got a transmission control transmitter.
In case the main computer fails.
And it goes with my sweater.
Ah, no good.
Why not?
This thing can only operate when it's got line of sight.
Hmm.
Hooper!
Kill indiscriminately!
Ah, somebody can tell Raymond Burr he's late.
Ugh.
Ew.
Ha ha, that tickles.
Ha ha, you guys.
He doesn't make me laugh.
Oh, cut it.
Cut it out.
Neat.
Throwing it all at him.
All those toy guns.
Come on, that guy's...
This isn't funny.
Oh, I'd like to thank the fine people of C-Topia
for giving me these totally useless arms.
You are going to die.
Do you know why?
Because I'm going to kill you.
Well, soldiers, was the fettuccine to your liking?
I trust the wine was palatable?
Good.
Kill them.
Hey, I can't take it.
Calgon, take me away.
Oh, that's so cruel for the rainforest, man.
I tell you.
Oh, sorry.
Making a mess.
Do everything.
Burn, burn, burn.
Yep.
It's our five dollar models there.
That was a road rally just blew up.
Well, it's worth a try.
Anything you can get, Godzilla.
Sure.
I'll take it.
If you can get Godzilla, sure.
But still.
Where'd Mickey Mouse go?
At the moment, he's still controlled by the computer.
I know, but this transmitter's signals
will override the computer controls.
I'm skeptical.
Well, let's give it a try.
Right.
I've enjoyed our time together.
Hey, you're listening to Laser 104,
so tune it in and rip the nab off.
(gunshots)
(laughing)
I love these puddles.
Boom.
Would you quit clowning and try to keep up?
Come with me.
You'll be my date.
Huh.
Hey, look, it's ugly John.
(engine revving)
Incoming wound.
(laughing)
Incoming wounded.
Attention all personnel.
I wonder if McLean Stevenson is on that chopper.
(laughing)
And what he's doing on that chopper.
Bye.
Woo hoo hoo.
Whee, this is the only fun, the most of it.
This is great.
He gives us all of that meme.
I've got a date with death.
Hey, he's doing the monster mash.
You know, mash with asterisks.
Yeah, thank you.
Yeah, no.
(engine revving)
(laughing)
Oh, what a rush that was on the screen.
Woo, wow.
Blow me away.
Saturday the 14th, I hate that movie.
(engine revving)
Huh?
Uh oh.
Woo.
Chad Jaguar, stop.
Whew, they're playing Chinese chicken.
Or is it Peking duck?
I can't.
That's right.
What the hell's happened?
He stopped.
Get Godzilla.
You'll find him on Monster Island.
Uh, wait, don't you want the address?
It's an emergency.
Everyone to get from street.
It's returned to the control of the earth people.
What is it doing now?
I'm in the shower.
To get Godzilla.
I see.
Um.
Well, stay where you are.
Sorry, sir.
Who knows?
You might get a chance to take it under control again.
I'm right.
Contact Star Hunter Universe M.
Say we need Gigan's help immediately.
And reverse the charges.
Additionally, notify our people on Easter Island.
Here they are.
His people on Easter Island.
Hmm.
Whoa.
Looks like he's having one of his episodes again.
Yep.
Look at it now.
It's all over the place.
Yeah, because it's lost its control.
Oh, we all get like that sometimes.
Get him some lithium.
I think so.
Tora, Tora, Tora.
Wrong decade.
Whoa.
Monster two zeros zero.
Uh, guys, he's very vulnerable right now.
This is not a good time to attack him.
Whew.
Ha ha.
Wow, who's flying that thing?
Henry Kissinger?
I think you got him.
Ha ha.
Overkill.
That's it.
Oh.
Dance.
Ouch.
Oh, that's a lot of work.
Dance.
Ouch.
Hey, it's a German air show.
Go ahead, four.
Ooh, crunch.
Mmm.
Hey, that's a good view of the fiery hell beast.
Ooh, neat.
Ha ha.
I won, I won, I'm the best.
I like my stuff.
It's fun.
Ah.
Yee, it's fun.
Meanwhile, in fashionable Palm Springs.
Wow, it really looks like a busy mall.
River place.
Yeah.
Hello there.
Anyone here?
Huh?
No.
Hey, we were just in this thing.
I recognize all these models.
Must have been evacuated.
That sounds pain.
I guess so.
Huh?
There it is.
That's it.
Wait, not joy.
We'll just borrow one.
What do you say?
I hope they got the right models for it.
Oh.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I'm here all week.
Zella has left the stadium.
I've got guests.
Oh, I hope I got cookies or something.
Hey, ooh.
Huh?
What's that?
Dad's trapped?
In a coal mine down in Dead Rock Canyon?
I understand.
Huh?
Oh, he forgot his semaphore flags.
He looks like a cheerleader.
Okay, look, I've got a few things to do,
but I'll be right there, okay?
You know, you could have phoned or something.
I mean, really, be reasonable.
Now my impression of Jack Nicholson at a Burger King.
Do this.
Neat.
Hmm?
Okay, here I come.
I can fly, I can fly, I can't fly.
Oh, I can swim.
Cannonball.
Can he swim?
And now Godzilla will attempt to swim the English Channel.
Good show, Godzilla.
Meanwhile, the tenderloin of San Francisco.
There goes the marina.
Sorry.
That guy's got the worst breath.
That always happens when you eat Japanese.
Oh, that happens after you eat anybody.
Uh, oh, no.
You know, I think lashing out like this
is really a sign of some deeper trouble.
It's really a cry for help.
Ooh.
I say, "Begone all you condos.
"Begone real estate that cost a million dollars an acre.
"Begone."
Now you're a suburb.
Get me.
I paved paradise and put in a parking lot.
Well, now we know why they're buying
all of our property and our movie studios.
The monsters?
Uh, can we talk?
We'll eliminate all the no-pest strips in Asia
if you'll just stop.
All right, who's next?
Osaka?
I'm coming, baby boy.
You're all saved in the last building.
(Mumbling)
He's killing good food.
I love the steam song.
Hmm.
Meanwhile, on an episode of "Then Came the Courtship of Bronson's Father"...
Oh, Mr. Eddy's father, I wish I were you.
Well, hang in there.
Come on, kid.
You know what?
We're gonna go get you some pants.
Come on. Shh.
Hmm.
Let's go.
Okay.
I think you should always wear protective headgear like that.
I like that.
Oh, cool.
What, are they at a Roy Lichtenstein exhibit all of a sudden?
Hey, is there an ethical question about taking a little kid on a dangerous mission?
Not this kid.
Yeah.
I can't bear to see you take these steps one more time.
Meet me at the top.
Gee, I hope this works or little Billy will be lunch meat.
Hmm?
(Gunshot)
Uh...
Oh, darn these Japanese products again.
Who?
Hello, Shil.
Was that an Oscar Wilde reference?
Uh, no, that was Shelley.
Laverne and Shelley.
Oh.
Oh, that's for Lady Windermere's fan.
And that's for a picture of Dorian Gray.
I'll harm you.
I'm glad I'm not there.
Hey, come on.
Kids heal faster.
They forget pain.
Get him, the little one.
Come on, Oscar.
I'm really glad I'm not there.
And that's for St. Joan.
Oh, no, that was Shaw.
(Gunshot)
Oh, shoot.
Now I'm here.
Oh, those stairs again.
I don't...
I don't believe this.
It's ridiculous.
Go.
Oh, you got him.
Yeah, just in time.
Want a helmet?
It worked out fine.
The robot's gone for Godzilla.
That's right.
Whoa.
We've got air conditioners hanging from the ceiling.
Amazing.
The monster's getting closer.
We better go.
What about him?
Oh, dress him up.
Something can't be.
Really dull him up.
(Gasping)
God damn it.
Pink belly.
Come on, leave him.
Let's go.
(Gunshot)
Whoa.